# Rabbi Hasan

Full Stack Developer having 3+ years of experience

I am a passionate programmer who loves to code, learn new things, and see progress on projects I am working on! It gives me a thrill when I solve a difficult problem. Interest both in Frontend, Backend. My goalis to become a fullstack developer. I enjoy gaining and sharing knowledge.



jasrabbi50@gmail.com

+8801681194424

Dhaka, Bangladesh

github.com/Rabbi50

linkedin.com/in/hasanrabbi

\_\_\_

stackoverflow.com/users/8266746/rabbi-hasan

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Full Stack Developer**

### Algorithm Generation Limited

10/2020 - Present,

Algorithm Generation Ltd was founded in 2015 to give the Business Process Automation arena of Bangladesh a fresh new look.

Tasks

- Working with a team. For collaboration I am using git.
- Working on development schedule task for send email.
- Developed rest API for mobile application.
- Developed a dynamic and responsive E-commerce and a Restaurant Web App UI and Admin Panel.
- Developed Product, Deep Nested Tree API, Multi-Role User JWT Authentication API.
- Manage Media File Like Images, Videos etc With Rest API.
- Built Role Management API for multiple users using DjangoRest Framework. Integrate API in client end using Ember.js Framework Ember data.
- Used Web sockets for real-time notification and real-time chat from server end to client end. For sending and receiving messages, used Django Channels on the server end and Ember.js framework add-on ember-WebSockets on the client end.
- Worked On Integrate SSLCOMMERZ Payment Gateway Api in server end used Django and built custom payment API and Also integrate payment API in client end used Ember.js.

Contact: Adnan Akter Tony

Email: adnan@adnanfoundation.com Phone:+8801714108478

## **Python Developer**

#### Securewp.net

04/2019 - 10/2020,

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

This company provides a WordPress security solution. They recover any hacked WordPress website and provide the best security solution.

Tasks

- Develop API for website vulnerability scan results with Django Rest Framework and Postgresql Database.
- Developed Responsive UI With React.js.
- Reserch About Javascript Malware.
- Built Website Vulnerability Scanner.

Contact: Tuhin Ahamed -

Email: tuhin@gmail.com Phone: +8801911986070

# **EDUCATION**

### **Bsc. In Software Engineering**

Daffodil International University 02/2015 - 10/2019, CGPA 3.60

# <u>SKILLS</u>

Javascript, ES6 Ember.js

Python Django

Postgresql Django Rest Framework

Celery Websockets

HTML Git
CSS3, SASS Linux

Bootstrap 4

## **PROJECTS**

Probashi Sheba (12/2021 - 06/2022)

 Probashi is an online platform to build & maintain rapport with Bangladeshi expatriates and aspirants for exchanging skills, experiences & services. I contribute to making this app backend. We used Django Rest API for exchanging data with the API end. We use Django Channel for realtime data exchange like messaging, notification, etc. <u>Application Link</u>

#### Website Vulnerability Scanner (10/2019 - 09/2020)

 Free online website scanner for hidden malicious links, hidden SEO spam, malicious javascript, check blacklist. Discover vulnerabilities and security holes in WordPress plugins, themes, core. Here i used Python, Django, Django rest api for server end and React.js for client end. Application Link

### E-commerce Web App (03/2021 - Present)

It's a multi-vendor type eCommerce application. Where seller can sell their
products and customer can buy their needs. Also build an admin panel for the
multi-role-based user. Here we are using Ember.js for the front-end and
Django Rest Framework for the back-end. For the database, we are using
Postgresql. Since this project is under development sometimes it goes
offline. Application Link

#### Resturant Web APP (04/2021 - Present)

It's a restaurant application. Where customers can order food, and book reservations. Also, customer can visualize their order processfrom the client end. Also, make a multi-role-based admin panel for this application. Here we are using Ember.js for the front-end and Django Rest Framework for the back-end. For the database, we are using Postgresql. Since this project is under development sometimes it goes offline. Application Link

#### PROBLEM SOLVING

#### LeetCode

(Ad-hoc problems, DS problems, Algorithm problems)

#### <u>HackerRank</u>

(Ad-hoc problems, DS problems, Algorithm problems)

## **LANGUAGES**

Bangla English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professionl Working Proficiency

# **INTERESTS**

Reading Books Problem Sol	lving Read Tech Blog	Traveling
---------------------------	----------------------	-----------